- Hello?
- Come downstairs.
You're signed in as Paul Lewis?
Why are you using a
defunct identity to get...
This has to stop.
Felix is active.
Charlie's okay. right?
Capture of these operatives
would constitute an immediate
strategic geopolitical disaster.
We have to get them
back. Whatever it takes.
You're being sent to Tehran to identify
Iranian nuclear engineers.
Professor mortazevi runs
an exchange program.
Your job is to be hired there.
How do I get a research job
at the institute of geophysics?
- That's your problem.
- Professor wartenburg.
- Hello.
- Hi.
Aren't you worried that a kid
can figure out your
super secret hiding place?
This isn't a game.
Why are you really in London?
Why am I being interrogated?
- Hey.
- Do I ask you why we only meet
when and where you say?
This isn't working.
Samia!
Civil war in Sudan had
been raging for years.
In the midst of fierce fighting.
refusing all peace talks
brokered by American
and Saudi diplomats.
no one could have guessed
both sides were in London.
meeting secretly with the Chinese.
On the table. billions in
infrastructure investment.
Control of oil fields to the south.
Gold mines in the north.
A home port on the red sea
- en route to the Suez canal.
- How are you?
Sudan was a triple
play. Everyone wanted in.
Us. the Russians. the Saudis.
Now here were the Chinese.
The worst part? We
knew nothing about it.
I have one role here.
To guarantee the secrecy of these talks.
No one discusses anything
outside of this room.
No one leaves their hotel at night.
Women are forbidden in hotels.
No press.
Any mistakes will terminate negotiations.
Before I. pick up where
we left off yesterday.
I would like to remind you all
of the general hemedti's central position
with regards to the
deadlock in Khartoum...
What was the nature of
the talks with the Sudanese?
What was at stake?
Only the future of their entire country.
Division of territory.
Safety of the clans.
Access to rich resources.
Between sufis. darfurians.
fall at as. rash aid as.
beja nomads. bedouins.
They needed an expert.
Someone who understood
the region. its history.
We see that villages
in the melut basin.
up to the white nile rift
are unhappy with this
administrative division
- into two provinces.
- Nobody knew
- that was samia zahir.
- We can learn
from the mistakes
made after the discovery
of the paloich oil field in South Sudan.
No woman had ever played a role
close to hemedti. or
with the Sudan mabahith.
Yet here she was. fighting
for the survival of her people.
The interests of the many ethnic groups
who live in these regions
cannot be bulldozed.
To end a bloody war.
Risking everything for peace.
Wanker.
Mecca's that way.
Brand-new building.
already we have mice.
Do you know. most of the rats in
New York City come from here?
Brown rat. Rattus norvegicus.
Listen. about what happened at the hotel
before you say anything.
- you already apologized.
- I did?
Well. no. but yeah.
I mean. no. you didn't. but yes. you did
in your own fucked-up way.
Well. I just wanted to say
thanks. It's obvious you don't.
But I appreciate your... trying.
Felix pretty much made up
for it. That was good work.
You know my fuck-up?
It was Charlie.
Last week. I called and
asked him the name of his op
to see if he was in danger.
I never should have done that.
Well. Henry. I mean...
That's way fucking worse.
I should report you. I mean. seriously.
You should be in jail for. like. 40 years.
All right. go on. then. I could use
a little me time right now.
You owe me one. but I owe you two.
One for Felix. one for Charlie.
Well. at least let me
buy you a mousetrap.
Okay.
We got a situation.
Fifth floor.
A Belarusian delegation is downstairs.
Some congressman from
Idaho called them a puppet state.
Lapdogs of put in.
Bosko's in there bailing water.
They want a public apology
or else they escalate.
- Who's on their team?
- The usual.
Assorted flunkies. senior attaché.
They're not room meat.
At least one will be kgb.
- I have an idea.
- What is it?
I'll rush the edge. you stun up the middle
and force a pass.
expose their quarterback.
Love it.
Fuck off. What do you want?
We need a word.
I've got the U.S. and
Belarus ambassadors in there
trying to avert a major
diplomatic incident.
We have an idea.
Is it better than. "we've lost an agent.
can we please get him back?"
Why are they here now?
'Cause some bum fuck.
no-name congressman
throws a little shade on capitol hill?
Maybe they want to
start a negotiation here.
If they do have coyote. they'll allude to it.
They'll give us a sign.
Open a back channel.
It'll be masked. Subtext.
We need to be in there to spot the sign.
- Owen.
- Sir?
- Walk away.
- Sir.
- Observers.
- Not a fucking word.
- Not a word.
I mean it.
These inflammatory comments.
widely reported in the press.
Your congressman from Iowa said.
and I quote. "Belarus is a failed state
we trust no more than North Korea."
Senior elected officials of
the United States of America.
insulting the reputation
of our great nation.
I'm sorry. Idaho.
Excuse me?
Mr. White. foreign policy.
Congressman Daniels is from Idaho.
Iowa has four
representatives in congress.
but not one of them has said
anything catty about Belarus. of late.
I have to say. either Idaho. i-Iowa. it's
not that it diminishes your central point.
that this is an insult to the
reputation of your country.
But it matters. does it
not. who actually said it.
But I-I interrupted.
Forgive me. Please continue.
What my colleague Mr. White is saying
is you're right. our countries
should respect one another.
trust one another.
But we don't. Why?
History.
Remember three years ago.
you lost a mig-35 over the baltic?
Precisely what I'm talking about.
We offered to support
search and rescue.
offered our surface radar.
You guys denied ever even having lost it.
I fail to see what relevance
- that has in this situation.
- Well.
if had been more
detail-focused and accurate.
on the same page.
the situation might have
been handled better.
Collaboratively.
Like here. today.
The one at the far end
of the table. thick-set.
- He's our guy.
- Yeah?
Because?
It was obvious.
He didn't say a word.
Him. I like.
Signal was clear.
Now we need to let them respond.
Through a less official channel.
How do you plan to do that?
They're still in the building.
Excuse me?
You've heard of this place?
Sure. You want to go?
I'm impressed you can understand us.
I studied Russian at
queen Mary here in London.
I can get the gist.
I see.
Pardon me.
- My name is mikhail.
- Tom Vincent.
Nice to meet you.
How about tomorrow. 10 P.M.?
You at the lanesborough?
Yeah. sure. Thank you.
Ready?
I hope so.
I hope so. too.
I mean. yeah. I'm-i'm... I'm ready.
Good. because your mission just started.
The institute of
geophysics is not a new job.
It is hostile ground. filled with enemies.
Targets.
Three types of enemy.
Your rivals.
Anyone who could be chosen
to go to Iran instead of you.
Exploit any weakness with prejudice.
Noble gas lab on the left.
And. this is the tims lab.
Tims?
Thermal ionization mass spec.
Of course.
That's Alice. She's looking at
- chondritic meteorites.
- Hi.
Early solar system stuff.
Friends.
Drop your guard. show weakness.
they'll exploit your mistakes.
Here's another mass spectrometer.
Eric. our visiting
volcanologist. We love him.
We're trying to make
him stay with us forever.
- Hi.
- If people like you. use it against them.
There's an sem. too. upstairs. of course.
Fair warning. though.
it gets busy. The team just back from
- the Iceland eruption...
- Enemy type three:
The predator.
The type you must be most wary of.
Never attack them head on.
You must seduce them. draw them in.
Can I help you?
Hi.
Did I get fired?
Is this your de... I'm so sorry.
I'm... they said wait here.
I'm Danny. the new research associate.
Hi. Rose. Danny...
Daniela more no a cost a.
Acosta... Spanish?
Studied in Madrid and just finished
my second degree in geophysics
at the university of Barcelona.
Did. did Manny show you around?
Yeah. Okay.
Manny and Danny. right?
I met most of the team.
Nice.
Who's that?
That is Reza.
He runs the exchange program.
He picks a candidate to take
back to Tehran for the year.
and everyone's sucking up.
Do you see. see that guy there?
That's Jerome.
He's Reza's human jockstrap.
He even plays squash with him.
So. everyone wants to go?
Are you fucking kidding me?
Like. Iranian tectonics is the shit. right?
Yeah.
Isn't it a... Isn't it a scary country?
What? I mean. sure. but it's just...
It's just so active. you know?
Yeah. Tell you what. I'll-I'll introduce you.
Come. come.
Professor mortazevi?
May I introduce Danny.
the new recruit from Spain.
postdoc Barcelona uni.
Nice to meet you. señorita.
Jerome. Hi.
- Hello.
- Do you play squash?
- Do you?
- No.
This guy spanks me every time.
Can't get within. like. five
points of him. basically.
But you love it. though. right?
Right. Well. we have about
45 minutes. so. rematch?
- Sure.
- Great.
Hasta luego.
See?
Right up his arse.
I've given up.
You don't want to go to Tehran?
Are you nuts? Of course I do.
It's just. the Iranians would
never take a girl. Ever.
Rose? Do you have a moment?
Hey.
Sorry. I meant to get back to you.
Have you seen much of London?
Our work here has kept me busy.
I know the city well.
London is for having fun
as well as working. Perhaps
I could show you around.
Mrs. Zahir. your husband
Dr. Mustafa called.
I told him you would return his call.
Excuse me.
You want anything else?
Some fruit?
Some cookies?
You got any blow?
Or. like. Ketamine?
Look.
I've only been a dad
for as long as you've been a daughter.
We're both making
this up as we go along.
But while you were
busy being a daughter.
I wasn't there.
We both know why. but that's no excuse.
So... I apologize.
And I would like
for us to try and make a fresh start.
That's all I got.
That's what my therapist
said you would say.
Really?
Small world. 'cause
that's what my therapist
told me to say.
You have a therapist?
- Actually. yes.
- Since when?
Since I got back.
That is... that's so fucked up.
Thank you.
No. dad. I'm serious.
That's like you telling me you joined.
like. a ballet school or something.
Thank you. I appreciate
it. and I'll pass it on.
I do think we need a fresh start. though.
We should Mark it.
do something together.
Like what?
You should...
Take me shopping and buy
me a bunch of shit I can't afford?
- Makes sense.
- Yeah.
whereupon I will forgive
you for everything.
- Everything?
- Everything. The whole nine.
All the pain. the confusion.
It shall vanish. Your
soul shall be wiped clean
by the pure clean waters
of a nearby shopping center.
We can do this. dad.
Together.
You're on.
So. how long you got?
An hour.
Okay. well. we do provide
a comprehensive. deluxe
60-minute soul cleansing service.
But the bad news is
it's twice as expensive
as the two-hour package.
Ooh.
Sold.
I got my student card as well.
Ten percent off. Treat
yourself. if you like.
Ten percent.
It's a deal.
Where do we start?
So. how is work?
Nonspecifically. broadly.
non-national security or
personally compromisingly?
Out of ten.
Minus two.
Are you still being followed?
By at least two separate parties.
Okay. How scared should I be?
Want to play a game?
Okay.
Won't you get in trouble
- for taking the piss like this?
- It's good for 'em.
Keeps them on their toes.
Plus. it's fun.
Come. Come on.
When did you last have
sex and with whom?
You go first.
I haven't had sex in 17 months.
Not since a... Messy
rebound fuck in a bar
after I separated with my husband.
I've been telling myself that
I'm concentrating on work.
moving countries. but
really I'm just scared.
It's been years since I dated and I
I found that a one-night
stand in Georgetown
just made me sad.
Is it my turn?
- Yes. it is.
- What was the question?
You know what the question was.
Not since I was in add is.
I was in a relationship.
one that you know about.
that I broke off because of my exfil.
- Do you miss her?
- I loved her.
I think so.
Whatever it was. whatever those feelings
they were more for her
than anyone I've ever met.
I don't know how many chances...
At feeling like that life gives you.
My guess is not many.
- That's hard to cope with.
- It's not hard.
It's impossible.
Unless you've spent your
whole life in training for it.
You seal it in a box. Bury it.
Do your job. Carry on.
Wounds heal.
They become stories.
Like that one on your hand.
Can you tell me how you came by it?
This?
Avocado pit.
Most of the damage in
an earthquake like this
is usually caused by the surface waves.
You can see here the staggered arrivals
of the different seismic
phases at stations
across the global
seismographic network.
But new instrumentation gives us
a more detailed picture than ever before.
Great job.
Thanks.
Are you familiar with
distributed acoustic sensing?
Of course.
Do you think you could
explain the technology.
say a few words about it?
Well. okay. I... I-I
worked on dark fiber data.
No. no. not now.
Later. at an event tonight.
At the well come library on euston road.
I'll pick you up.
Let's say 6:30?
T-T-Tonight?
Sure.
Great.
And it's black-tie.
You'll need a dress.
Hello. Elements spa.
I need a leg wax appointment.
Not at the spa. We do home visits.
I was. I was really
hoping... it's that or nothing.
Okay. Let me give you my address.
I can. I can be there
in about half an hour.
Sorry.
How did you get into my apartment?
Any more dumb questions?
You said this was urgent.
At 7 P.M. in front of
every expert in the country
at some black-tie fundraiser.
I have to deliver an overview
from my direct experience of
distributed acoustic sensing.
What's that?
I have no idea. but it's on my résumé.
How many pages can you
memorize fast? Ten? 20?
20 to 25.
25 an hour?
25 in total.
- How'd it go with Dr. Blake?
- Good.
Say no more.
Do you have a second?
Simon. how can I help you?
I got more on that target for you.
She's not a target. she's a poi.
What have you got?
Yes. so. since April 2018.
she taught at the Addis
Ababa central university.
And the last three months.
she's been a visiting fellow
at the public university of Khartoum.
and. she was elected head
of the Sudanese center
for cultural heritage.
She ever disappear
for any length of time?
A few days even?
Any contact with
ministry of internal affairs
or the security departments?
No. the only unusual thing
was contact with a lawyer in Khartoum.
It looks like she's getting a divorce.
It's unusual in her
culture but not unheard of.
Maybe not relevant to your focus.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah.
The divorce is real. Lawyer's real.
They filed it and started proceedings.
I mean. the war's upped
divorces by. like. 50%.
Very good.
Back scattered signals
from imperfections
in the optic fiber that backs...
Fuck. The interrogation unit
receives back scattered signals...
Imperfections in the optic fiber.
Interrogation unit receives
back scattered signals...
From imperfections in the optic fiber.
Acoustic waves change
the fiber's signal shape.
converting... no... altering...
The acoustic waves
change the fiber's shape.
altering the back scattered signals.
which can be converted to strain rate.
Acoustic waves
change the fiber's shape.
altering the back
scattered signal's phase.
which can be converted to strain rate.
No.
Fuck! No.
No!
Fuck!
Fuck.
Spectral analysis of
frequencies in the signal...
Can identify seismic phases.
Spectral analysis of
frequencies in the signal
can identify seismic phases.
- All ready?
- Totally.
All right. let's go.
Do you have a phone
charger in your car?
Sorry. I don't.
Sorry I didn't have a charger.
Not a problem.
Networks from unused
telecommunication.
infrastructures can-can
be uti... can be utilized.
I'm sorry?
Nothing.
Going over my speech.
Lot of important people there.
Relax. This is a home game for you.
Your specialist subject. right?
Teach us what you know.
You're smart.
Extremely impressive.
I'm not sure I've known
anyone quite like you.
With your focus. your intelligence.
I'd like to see you outside work.
It's something I've thought about a lot.
I don't think this is a good idea.
I'm sorry. it's
your eyes.
My eyes?
They remind me of my father's.
Your father's.
How old is your father?
He died when I was six.
He was 35.
- I'm sorry to hear that.
- All I remember
are his kind. sweet. soulful eyes.
Soon as I saw you. that's
who you reminded me of.
Listen. I'm
I'm hugely flattered an-an-and
I enjoy working with you a lot.
Of course. but I-I understand.
Listen. this event we're going to
is the institute's biggest night of the year.
I can see how nervous you are.
Maybe it's kinder to let someone
with more experience make the address.
Jerome. perhaps.
I can let you out here.
Wait. I'm-I'm not even coming?
No. there's really no need.
It's fine. I don't want you to be anxious.
- See you in the office.
- Okay.
We have nothing like this in Minsk.
We're not in Kansas anymore.
Yeah. I can see.
I love it here. Anything goes.
Tell me about it.
Last week my bike
got stolen around here.
Lot of crime in London?
Had it 20 years.
It had my phone number
engraved on the crossbar.
If the guy who stole it called me.
I'd give him five times what it's worth.
Like that jet.
In our meeting?
Your mig fighter that
vanished over the baltic?
I-I don't follow you.
I mean. if you lose something
and you really want it back.
maybe it's worth more than face value.
A lot more.
Ask me if I'd buy my bike back.
I'd say. "name your price."
You're very... Sentimental.
Call me old-fashioned.
If you're ever back in
London for a night out
or just to talk about
anything. this is my number.
- Great evening.
- Stick around.
I got work in the morning.
- Enjoy yourself.
- Good luck with your bike.
Who knows? You may get that call.
Henry.
What are you reading?
Gulf war?
You need a hobby. my friend.
It's just out. Great read.
Like you have hobbies.
What the hell is this?
You believe I painted that?
Not for a moment. When
do you have time for that?
I don't.
I carry that around to remind me
that somewhere in me
is the guy who once did.
Got a million of them.
The line's open.
How do we know he's legit?
He knew what we want.
May take some time
to filter up the chain.
but the line's open.
- What if it's a shakedown?
- It's always possible.
All right.
You guys get some rest.
Both of you. You look like ghosts.
No. no. you keep it. It
was really lucky for me.
You might need it.
This works. I'm sending that
congressman a fruit basket.
Yep.
Good old congressman Daniels.
Whose son was stopped
at Miami airport in 2014
with a half kilo of cocaine.
The honorable gentleman
from the 2nd district remains
extremely grateful to Langley to this day.
- Fuck off.
- Wait. you made him do it?
You got a U.S. congressman
to sound off in congress about Belarus.
I didn't make him do anything.
I may have gently suggested it.
- Mom?
- Hey.
I know. I know.
Yeah.
Can you tell me how you came by it?
This?
Avocado pit.
- Hey.
- No military rule.
No military rule!
Lock the door.
Where are you going?
To find a way out.
Sami.
Let's go.
- Your hand.
- It's okay.
Why didn't you stop?
Because I was falling.
When you fall. when you really fall.
you never know how far it is.
After a while. it feels like flying.
Then you hit the ground.